Chapter 2

Once again, Cedric stood in the center of his team as they lined up on the midfield line. "Are we going to play a fair game this time, Harry?"

"No."

"No?" The yellow-clad squad visibly bristled. Hufflepuffs held hard work and fair play in high regard, and last of the Potters wasn't even trying to conceal his skulduggery.

"No, because that wouldn't be interesting. My team is composed entirely of first years, two of them scared of flying, and a third riding a stick older than the school's Cleansweep Sevens."

"Watch it, Potter! I'm only doing this as a favor to General Granger."

Harry continued in stride while Hermione pulled Ron aside. "If we were to play fair, there would be no contest. The Hufflepuff house team is so overwhelmingly favored to win that you can't even savor the victory. I mean, how much pride can you take in crushing a team of, effectively, four and a half first years? In short, if we play fair -- meaning with no tricks up our sleeves -- it still wouldn't be a fair game -- meaning a relatively even match where both sides have a decent chance of victory."

"I see." Cedric folded his arms across his chest. "You know, there are other reasons to play a friendly game of quidditch."

Harry paused. "Such as?"

"Spending the afternoon with friends. The simple joy of flying, especially in weather like this." Today's sky was unusually bright and clear for Scotland. "And there are some things about a real game that drills can't quite provide, so mixing them with what our Defense professor would call 'live-fire exercises' is good practice."

"Ah." Harry looked and felt properly chagrined. His mind flashed back to the first Battle Magic class of the year, the day Professor Quirrell outed him as the most dangerous student in the year. The intent to kill, the will to win. "Well, I'm afraid playing us in a fair game wouldn't give your team much practice. But I can offer you a game against a team with unusual tactics. Since I have not been indoctrinated by Quidditch Through the Ages or traditional modes of thought, I can offer an outside perspective."

Said Cedric, with a smirk, "Some how, Mr. Potter, I'm not sure we could use your 'techniques' in an official quidditch game."

"Almost certainly. That is, if they were caught." Harry noticed the seven Hufflepuffs, all older and taller than him, now also looked considerably colder. The glares from behind him weren't much better. "Not that I would do that in a serious game, but Slytherin house does have a certain reputation. Furthermore, highlighting certain exploitable aspects of quidditch may lead us to think of legal innovations."

The Hufflepuff captain turned to his team. A couple of them were as curious as he was. Heidi just rolled her eyes and gave him a 'whatever' face. "All right, Harry, we're still interested."

"Excellent. See if you discover what the technique is and try to counter it."

Diggory pulled his wand out of the dueling holster hidden underneath his quidditch robes. "Suppose I just cast Finite Incantatem on you right now."

Harry bowed. "Then you win. Hermione and I are the only ones here who can cast the charm. If you dispel it each time we recast it, even working together, we would reach magical exhaustion before you. Shall we see how the game would have gone?"

Cedric cracked a grin and stowed his wand back up his sleeve. "Let's see what you've got, Harry."

---===tvtropeswillruinyourlife===---

snap

Fourteen players kicked off the sun baked grass and launched into the air. Immediately, Harry went into an oval search pattern. Cedric followed, keeping one eye on Harry and whatever his "technique" was and another out for the snitch.

Except the Ravenclaw was flying far faster than seekers normally flew. A seeker going at top speed might cover more ground, but it became really hard to spot the snitch when everything was a blur.

Cedric kicked his broom to match speed, but his eyes had real trouble scanning around him, so he mostly concentrated on Harry instead.

Ten - zero.

As far as Cedric could tell, other than flying far faster than typical, Harry was acting normally: speeding up and slowing down and making slight course adjustments to get a better look at things that caught his eye.

Twenty - zero.

Tracey accidentally fouled a Hufflepuff chaser. But while the two teams set up the penalty shot, the two seekers continued to circle.

Thirty - zero.

The truth was that the first year chasers were so insubstantial that the 'Puffs probably would have scored more goals continuing play as normal rather than stopping the action to arrange the penalty.

Forty - zero.

Ron made a miraculous save, but then Heidi beat Neville to the rebounding quaffle and did a neat Finbourgh Flick from a tricky angle. The red quaffle glanced off the rim of the hoop and through.

Fifty - zero.

Cedric saw Harry dive and, yes, there was the snitch. One of the Hufflepuff beaters, Maxine, knocked a bludger on an intercept course. Susan managed to deflect it away from Harry, though she hadn't thought through where she should hit it, and it started chasing Hermione instead. Cedric was still a good three broom lengths behind when Harry's fingers closed over the snitch.

---===tvtropeswillruinyourlife===---

Harry handed the practice snitch back to the Hufflepuff captain, who had checked the balls for this game out from Madam Hooch. "Do you have a hypothesis?"

Cedric tallied the evidence. "You admitted using a charm that could be dispelled by Finite, and you flew way faster than normal for seekers. So my guess is your charm helps you see better. I don't suppose you turned your glasses into omnioculars?"

"Interesting idea. Zoom and playback features could help search for the snitch, but no, that's not it." The two teams settled themselves in the stands while Harry passed around fourteen chilled butterbeers from out of his mokeskin pouch, his compensation to the others for participating in the experiment. "Before I explain, I should mention that, while doing background research, I verified a story about a Hogwarts match played during a rainstorm. A third-year seeker had Impervius cast on his glasses to keep the rain out of his eyes. This implies that using magic to assist vision is allowed."

Cedric swallowed his mouthful of butterbeer. "Something tells me your spell is a lot more game breaking than Impervius."

"True. What do you look for when hunting the snitch?"

"Well, a glint or streak of gold is a good clue."

"Exactly, the primary identifying feature of the snitch is that it shines like gold. What makes gold look like gold is that it reflects almost all of the light that hits it, especially red and yellow, though blue not so much. And muggle scientists have discovered that, if you look at a rainbow and move from yellow to orange to red and past the colors we can see, there is still more light that human eyes are not adapted to see. Furthermore, gold and other metals reflect this light pretty well.

"So my second idea was to charm my eyes or my glasses to see this invisible color. Then if I shine the quidditch pitch with this light, I could more easily spot metallic objects while everyone else would see nothing, though they might notice they were warmer than expected. There were two flaws with this plan, however. First, muggle devices that can shine a directed beam of this light won't work in Hogwarts. Second, since wizards don't know about this light, of course there wouldn't be a spell to see it."

Harry took a swig from his bottle. "But my third idea paid off. After some research, I found a spell that became popular among North American wizards during the mid-nineteenth century and asked Professor Flitwick to teach Hermione and me." Harry removed his glasses and handed them to Cedric.

Cedric held them up to his face but did not put them on. A couple teammates peered over his shoulder. Even in the dimming afternoon sun, the snitch laying secured in the quidditch supply trunk glowed like a beacon. So did the silver lettering on the open case. "Amazing, Mr. Potter."

"I learned about the spell in a book on goblins and Gringotts. During the various gold rushes, prospecting wizards used it to detect precious metals. Similar spells are used in transfiguration and potions to detect metals."

"It is an interesting idea, Harry, but it wouldn't be allowed in a real game. What you describe sounds like using Lumos to search for a snitch during night games, but that's explicitly prohibited."

"Yes, I noticed that when I was reading the rulebook for loopholes to exploit. I do see what Professor Quirrell was saying about it being odd that the wizarding sport doesn't involve any spellcasting."

"Apparently even simple spells can grant huge advantages, so prohibiting magic seems to be the best way to have a fair game."

"I thought about that too. What if I only used magic to give myself a disability? Shouldn't it be legal to handicap myself?"

Cedric grinned slyly. "Why do I think that your 'handicap' isn't really one?"

"Fine." Harry didn't think a fourth year army general would fall for so obvious a lure. "My fourth idea was to find a spell that removed my ability to see all colors except gold. Or failing that, everything except yellows."

Cedric shook his head. "Your reputation is well-earned, General Chaos. Though that spell would make it hard to tell who is on which team. So, you've mentioned idea two through four. Are there more? What was the first?"

Harry stood up. "To demonstrate my first idea, I have to make a floo call."

---===tvtropeswillruinyourlife===---

Cedric greeted Harry's replacement seeker, who was almost entirely encased in leather armor. "Honor to meet you. But, Harry, I do think we would have noticed this one."

"That's why there were ideas two through four. Shall we run the experiment?"

Upon the instant the game started, the seeker made a beeline for something only he could see. Cedric gamely gave chase. Anthony and Maxine belted both bludgers at the new seeker, knowing it would be their only chance to interrupt Harry's plan.

The seeker dodged both easily. Bludgers were far slower than spells.

The second game ended 150 to 0 and lasted all of seventeen seconds.

Back on the ground, Harry made introductions, though some students continued to stand well back. "Everyone, this is Alastor Moody."

Chapter 3

"Is the plan to make us bored or anxious through waiting, Mr. Potter?" joked Cedric. The Hufflepuff house team and six of Harry's first year team were scattered around the center of the pitch. With nothing better to do, some were chatting among themselves, others were maintaining or doing tricks on their brooms. Only Hermione was missing, and Cedric had been keeping an eye out for her, in case she was setting up part of Harry's scheme.

"Nope. Our seventh player is just really really busy. Oh, there he is." A hunched figure shambled onto the pitch. Maybe he was late because he had been dragging his feet the whole way from his office. Harry sighed. "And this cost me a lot of Quirrell points."

Harry walked over then stopped short, tossing Professor Quirrell the broom instead of handing it to him. The zombie made a weak attempt to catch the broom but missed, and it flopped onto the wet grass.

Harry sighed again. "A lot of points." Turning to Cedric, he asked, "Shall we get started?"

Cedric considered. Zombie Quirrell might just be an act, since Harry and Professor Quirrell together must have come up with something diabolical. "Was today's scheme your idea or Professor Quirrell's or both?"

"Oh no, I brought it to Professor Quirrell but needed his help to carry it off. Professor Quirrell would have charged me ten times as many points if he had to come up with the idea as well. Up!" The last remark was directed at Harry's borrowed broom, which leaped eagerly into his hand.

"All right, Mr. Potter." Cedric mounted his broom. Without glancing over his shoulder, he knew his team had done the same.

Harry waited until the keepers had reached their respective ends of the pitch and waved that they were ready. snap

Cedric kicked off hard and pushed his Cleansweep Seven to maximum acceleration. But as he alternated scanning the skies and checking he wasn't about to hit anyone, Cedric realized he couldn't see Harry or Professor Quirrell. Going into full scan mode, he saw Harry already heading for the ground where Professor Quirrell stood. It looked like Professor Quirrell hadn't even picked up the broom.

As Cedric touched down nearby, Professor Quirrell -- standing upright and no longer a zombie -- said with a tired tone, "Will that be all, Mr. Potter?" In his right hand was the golden snitch, flapping in vain.

"Yes, thank you for your time, Professor." The Battle Magic professor's jaw went slack, as did his hand, allowing the snitch to flutter off. Zombie Professor Quirrell shuffled back in the direction of the castle.

---===tvtropeswillruinyourlife===---

The two teams, minus Quirrell and Hermione, settled into the bleachers. Once again, Harry pulled butterbeers out of his pouch and handed them around.

"You know, it's good manners to tell the other team who is playing which position," commented Cedric. "Since you were seeker both previous games, I assumed you were still seeker and Professor Quirrell was filling in for your missing chaser."

"Then I apologize." Harry handed Cedric a chilled bottle while trying to look sufficiently contrite. "Being muggle-raised and not growing up playing quidditch, I was unaware."

"It's all right." Cedric popped open his bottle with stylish flick of his wand. "The thing is, Professor Quirrell knows so much magic that we could sit here all afternoon and still not guess what the trick was."

"The search space is rather large," agreed Harry, "So here's a clue: all he used was a fourth-year spell." One of the Hufflepuffs coughed when some butterbeer went down the wrong pipe.

"Just a fourth-year spell?" asked Cedric, confused. "Then why did you need Professor Quirrell to pull it off?"

"Actually, I needed him for something else. Clearly, Professor Quirrell used some magic to cheat that is illegal under the rules of quidditch. If this were an official game, what would then happen?" At that moment, Harry looked remarkably like Professor McGonagall cold calling a student in class with a question.

"Well..." Cedric riffled through the stories of infamous quidditch matches he had heard about. "I guess cast prior incantato on his wand."

"Right. Of course, Professor Quirrell wouldn't just hand over his wand and leave himself exposed like that. But let's say he did allow it and prior incantato showed nothing incriminating, such as a scouring charm or something."

Cedric knew this one from reading auror procedural novels. "Then he cast the scouring charm sometime between catching the snitch and giving up his wand to throw people off. But there are ways to extend the reverse spell effect to see more of the wand's history."

"And what if that also turned up nothing?" Cedric's brow wrinkled. "Remember, this is why I needed Professor Quirrell and not just any fourth year."

"So you needed Professor Quirrell," thought Cedric aloud, "But not for him to use his wand. But why would you need a powerful wizard and all the spells at his disposal but not his wand?"

Anthony, one of the Hufflepuff beaters, suggested, "He got Professor Quirrell to intimidate the snitch?"

"No, Harry did say a fourth-year spell was involved." Cedric clapped his gloved hands together. "I got it! Wandless magic!"

Harry grinned. "It would have been a bit of a giveaway if I started waving my wand around during the game. Professor Quirrell also cast it wordlessly too, in case someone overheard him. And have you guessed what spell I suggested Professor Quirrell use?"

"It's in the fourth year curriculum?" asked Cedric. Harry nodded. "It's most likely a charm. So that means... Ah! Accio!"

Harry applauded Cedric's deduction. "May I demonstrate?" Harry pulled his wand from his wrist holster. After Professor Quirrell had released the snitch, no one had caught the snitch, so it was still flitting about the stadium. Harry made a circle then a downward motion. "Accio!"

Seconds passed but nothing happened. Harry shrugged and adopted the tone of a lecturer. "The summoning charm is a very versatile spell. For example, I read that a couple seventh years summoned their brooms through a locked door but then got the brooms to navigate through the hallways of Hogwarts." Harry took a deep breath, gathering his magic again. He pointed to a different part of the stadium. "Accio!"

Still nothing happened, though Harry was breathing more heavily now. "But the story that really got me thinking was about this book thief. She suspected that some rare books were hidden in an office, but she didn't know where in the office or even if they were there. But she cast accio and, sure enough, the books came floating out. And that is why anti-summoning charms should be standard in anti-burglary wards. Accio!"

Still no snitch. "Bottom line, accio doesn't just summon objects, it also searches for objects. Of course, the more precisely you know the location of the object, the easier it is to cast. Professor Quirrell, even wandless, can search more efficiently than I am doing. But searching a quidditch pitch is just a matter of time. Accio!" A streak of gold flew into Harry's palm. "Just because it isn't an OWL- or NEWT-level spell doesn't mean it's not useful."